# **KEVIN LONG**

Austin, TX | 512-975-0082 | kevinjlong75@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/klong75</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/KLong75</u> | Portfolio: <u>kevinlong.dev</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Software Engineer. Based in Austin, TX. Background in the performing arts and education. Brings the passion and creativity of an artist, combined with the patient persistence, and skilled communication of a teacher, to work as a software engineer. Thrives on creative problem-solving and collaboration. Experienced at meeting deadlines under pressure. Loves the challenge of attempting to answer the question, "What if?".

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS, Responsive Web Design, Agile Methodology, Object-Oriented Programming, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, React, React Hooks, React Router, React Context, Material UI, Node, SQL, Sequelize, MySQL, Bootstrap, GitHub, Git Version Control, Google Fonts, Heroku, bcrypt, JSON Web Tokens, Handlebars, jQuery, Model-View-Controller, PWA, Service Workers, Email.js

#### **PROJECTS**

**Vain Mainstream -** The official web application for indie rock musician Vain Mainstream. SPA. Installable PWA with offline functionality. Users can listen to audio, download MP3s, watch embedded videos, and share on social media.

GitHub: github.com/KLong75/vain-mainstream | Deployed: vainmainstream.com

- **Role:** development, design, sole author
- Tools: React, Material UI, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Google Analytics, Google Fonts

**MUSICOLOGY** - Full Stack (MERN) social networking application for musicians.

GitHub: github.com/KLong75/musicology | Deployed: musicology-umekev.herokuapp.com/

- Role: Primary author and project manager
- **Tools:** MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, React, Node.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Material UI, bcrypt, JSON web tokens, Google Fonts

#### **RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineer, Freelance - Remote

Oct 2022 - Present

Design, Develop, Update, and Maintain fully responsive web applications that meet client specifications, exceed client expectations, function well, are intuitive to use, and look great on any screen size.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Vain Mainstream Indie Rock Musician vainmainstream.com
  - Designed and developed SPA/PWA from client specifications
  - o Optimized audio and image compression resulting in 20% faster website
  - Update weekly with new audio and video tracks as they are released by client
  - Support client social media campaign with Google Analytics data
- Sam Hahn Travel Travel Agency klong75.github.io/sam-hahn-travel
  - Designed and developed SPA/PWA from client specifications.
  - Adjust design based on client feedback

## **Bootcamp Teaching Assistant, 2U - Remote**

October 2022 - Present

Assist with instruction of the Full Stack Web Development Curriculum. Support students with class activities, homework assignments, projects, and technical issues.

## **Key Accomplishment:**

• Plan and facilitate bi-weekly homework help sessions based on student need resulting in a 15% increase in student homework submissions.

**1st & 2nd Grade Teacher, Austin Discovery School - Austin, TX June 2020 - June 2021**Utilized clear communication and critical thinking skills to develop and implement lesson plans for all subjects across two grade levels.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- Used no-code platform Seesaw in conjunction with several other learning applications to successfully develop and implement an innovative online learning system for virtual learning, allowing students to learn effectively from home with minimal hands-on support from parents and guardians resulting in a 25% increase in assignment completion.
- Through virtual learning, assisted two struggling students in improving their reading assessment scores to on-target levels.
- Earned State Teaching Certification from Texas Education Agency

### **Theater Artist, Various Companies - Multiple Locations**

June 1998 - Feb 2019

Worked with several theater companies in various capacities including puppeteer, actor, director, technical director, lighting designer, set designer, and theater technician.

# **Key Accomplishments:**

- Performed in 18 states and 2 foreign countries (South Korea and The Dominican Republic)
- Staff Artist for MayDay Parade and Festival (2001, 2006 2012) annual outdoor giant puppet spectacle produced by In The Heart of the Beast Puppet and Mask Theater involving hundreds of performers and attended by tens of thousands in Minneapolis, MN.
- While on Mayday Staff worked to streamline the post-parade clean-up process, resulting in a 20% reduction in clean-up time.

### Department Buyer, Linden Hills Co-op - Minneapolis, MN

June 2004 - Aug 2013

Department profitability, inventory management, ordering of all products to be sold, establishing and maintaining relationships with vendors, receiving orders, supervising stocking of all items received, researching new items, customer service, etc.

#### **Key Accomplishment:**

 Used Point of Sale software to maintain an electronic perpetual inventory of all items received and sold by the frozen department. Utilized perpetual inventory to auto generate purchase orders for goods to be sold in the frozen department. Resulted in department wide profit margin increase of 15% and a labor savings of approximately 12 hours per week.

## **EDUCATION**

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University of Texas

Austin, TX

Bachelor of Arts in Theater Truman State University

Kirksville, MO